Guide to the John O'Toole Papers, 1954-1990 and undated RL.00983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1968-1990 and undated, 10 boxes
  - New York Times, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Newspapers of the Future, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Newsweek, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Nominating Committee, 1981 (Box 20)
  - North Castle Partners, 1982-1985 (Box 20)
  - Northwestern University
    - General files, 1981-1984 (Box 20)
    - Fundraising, 1957-1985 (Box 20)
    - Institute of Modern Communications, 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - O, miscellaneous, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Ogilvy, David, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Organization, 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - O'Toole, John
    - Interviews, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Memos to the Organization, 1973-1985, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - P, miscellaneous, 1981-1985 (Box 21)
  - People Weekly, 1982-1985 (Box 21)
  - Phil Donahue Show interviews, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Political Advertising, 1982-1985 (Box 21)
  - Public Service
    - General files, 1981-1982, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Contributions, 1982 (Box 21)
    - Solicitations, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Q, miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Regency Hotel, 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - Research, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Responses, Cannes, CLIO winners, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Retirement Letters, 1985, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - S, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - San Francisco Office, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Staff memos, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Strategy Board, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Subscriptions, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Syracuse University, Newhouse School of Public Communications, 1986 (Box 22)
  - T, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Tournament of Roses, 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - U, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - U.S. Government, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - University of Illinois, 1982-1985 (Box 23)
  - U.S. News and World Report, 1982-1985 (Box 23)
  - V, miscellaneous, 1983-1985 (Box 23)
  - W, miscellaneous, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Worldwide Account Directors Newsletter memos, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
  - Z, miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 23)
  - 100 Best Television Commercials, 1981 (Box 23)
- International Offices, 1968-1985 and undated, 3 boxes
  Contains reports, correspondence, and organizational information related to the operations of FCB's international offices. Also includes itineraries from O'Toole's trips to visit several of these offices. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Amsterdam, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Assessment of Agencies in Taiwan and Korea, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Athens, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Auckland, New Zealand, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Australia trip, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Barcelona, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Brussels, 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - Buenos Aires, 1983 (Box 23)
  - Cape Town, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Caracas, 1983 (Box 23)
  - Copenhagen, 1981-1985 (Box 23)
  - Creative Directors, International, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Creative reviews, 1982-1984 (Box 23)
  - Financial reports, 1981 (Box 23)
  - FCB International Committee, 1981 (Box 23)
  - FCB International, Inc., 1981, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Frankfurt, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Germany, Private, 1982 (Box 24)
  - Hamburg, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Hong Kong, 1981-1984 (Box 24)
  - International organization, 1982-1985 (Box 24)
  - International partnerships, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Jamaica, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Johannesburg, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Kuwait and Lebanon, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Latin America, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Lisbon, 1982 (Box 24)
  - London, 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Madrid, 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Melbourne, 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Memoranda, 1982 (Box 24)
  - Mexico City, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Milan, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Montreal, 1981, 1983, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Paris, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Rome, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Rotterdam, undated (Box 25)
  - Sao Paolo, 1981-19855, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Singapore, 1983-1984 (Box 25)
  - Stockholm, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Sydney
    - General files, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Australia research, 1982 (Box 25)
    - GRID Presentation to Clients, 1982 (Box 25)
  - Tokyo
    - General files, 1983-1985 (Box 25)
    - FCB Presentation, undated (Box 25)
    - McKinsey Study, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Toronto, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - United Kingdom, 1981 (Box 25)
- Meetings, 1970-1985, 5 boxes
  Contains correspondence, memoranda, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to meetings of FCB staff and of various advertising organizations. Also includes files related to luncheons and dinners of FCB staff, advertising organizations and various societies outside of the advertising business. Items arranged by meeting title and then by date.
  - Advanced Advertising Program, 1982-1985 (Box 25)
  - Adweek Seminar, 1984 (Box 25)
  - American Irish Historical Dinner, 1982 (Box 25)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1982-1984, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Association of National Advertisers
    - Annual Meeting, 1984 Nov. (Box 25)
    - Workshop, 1984 May (Box 25)
  - Audit Bureau of Circulations Conference, 1982 Nov. 11 (Box 25)
  - Australian Association of National Advertisers Conference, 1982 Oct. (Box 25)
  - Board of Directors meeting files, 1982-1985, 1 of 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Board of Directors meeting files, 1982-1985 (continued), 2-5 of 5 folders (Box 26)
  - Cosmopolitan International Conference, 1982 Oct. 18 (Box 26)
  - Creative Conference, 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Creative Directors Meetings, 1971, 1982, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Executive Council Meetings
    - General files, 1982-1985, 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Steering Committee, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Executive Directors Conference, 1983 (Box 27)
  - Finance Committee minutes
    - Minutes, 1981-1985, 10 folders (Box 27)
    - Presentation to FCB Communications Board, 1985 May 8 (Box 27)
  - Flame of Truth Award Dinner, 1983 Jan. (Box 28)
  - FCB Annual Meeting, 1982-1985, 5 folders (Box 28)
  - International Advertising Association Symposium, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Latin American Creative Directors Meeting, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Luncheons, 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Marketing Communications Executives International Lunch, Marketing Communication of the Year, 1982 May 26 (Box 28)
  - Marketing Conference, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Merger Discussion Meeting, 1983 Sept. (Box 28)
  - New York Management Committee Meeting material, 1981 (Box 28)
  - New York Office
    - Management Group Meetings, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Summit Meetings, 1970 (Box 28)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts, 1982 1984, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - New York University Business Forum Luncheon, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Notes for I.C.I. Conference, 1984 Sept. 18 (Box 28)
  - Only One Earth Dinner, 1983 Feb. (Box 28)
  - Paintline International Conference, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Research Directors Meeting agenda, 1982 (Box 28)
  - Tracy-Locke Advertising, Discussion Outline for Meeting with Norm Campbell, 1981 Feb. 26 (Box 28)
  - U.S. Executive Creative Directors
    - Conference, 1984 Feb. (Box 28)
    - Meeting, 1983 May (Box 28)
  - World New Products Conference, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Worldwide Account Directors (WWAD) (Box 29)
    - Conference, 1982 Apr. (Box 29)
    - Meetings, 1983-1985, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Worldwide Managers Meetings, 1980-1985, 8 folders (Box 29)
- New Business, 1970-1985, 2 boxes
  Contains materials related to the attempts of FCB to acquire new accounts. The bulk of the materials include drafts and scripts of general agency presentations designed for prospective clients. Also includes reference materials relating to these presentations and research reports relating to particular markets, such as food and liquor. Some materials document the agency's general strategies for acquiring new business. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Agency Credentials Presentation, 1982, 1984, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Breakthrough Advertising Presentations, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Creative files, 1981 (Box 29)
  - Creative Presentation to P.F.I., 1982 (Box 29)
  - Evaluating Campaigns Presentation, 1984 (Box 29)
  - FCB New York Orientation, 1983 Nov. 2 (Box 29)
  - Idea Planning Model, 1982 (Box 29)
  - Learning Chip Food Presentation, 1984 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous files, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous creative files, 1982-1985 (Box 29)
  - Multinational Prospects (Box 30)
    - General files, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Status Reports, 1983-1985 (Box 30)
  - New Business, general files, 1981 (Box 30)
  - New Business Plan, 1981 (Box 30)
  - New and Lost Business Status Report, 1981 (Box 30)
  - New York Office Credentials Presentation, 1981 (Box 30)
  - O'Toole reels and slides, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Positioning Strategy, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Presentation, general, 1970 (Box 30)
  - Prospect lists and Prospect Evaluation System, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Questionnaire reply, 1970 Mar. 16 (Box 30)
  - Rationale for a Corporate Communications Wing for FCB, 1981 (Box 30)
- Personnel, 1969-1985, 3 boxes
  Includes materials on FCB personnel organization and management, employee transfers, salaries, benefits and loans. Also includes resumes of prospective employees. The series has been divided into Open Files and Restricted Files subseries.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restrictions on Access: Files relating to individuals' employment are closed for 25 years from the date of the individual employee's death, or 40 years from the date of termination if the date of death cannot be determined.
  - Open Files
    Contains general information and blank forms relating to FCB personnel policies. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphatebically.
    - Affirmative Action Reports, 1982-1985 (Box 30)
    - Bonus Plan, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Creative Director job description, 1973 (Box 30)
    - Employee benefits, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Manpower Planning and Costing, 1981 (Box 30)
    - Minority Groups, 1981 (Box 30)
      [Includes list of inappropriate advertisements.]
    - New York Office Research Director, 1982 (Box 30)
    - O'Toole Assistant, job duties, 1983 (Box 30)
    - Part-time Employment for Employee Directors, 1977 (Box 30)
    - Salary Procedures, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Restricted Files
    Contains resumes, salary figures, and correspondence pertaining to specific employees. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
    - General files, 1981, 1983, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Applications, 1982-1985, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Baker, Bill, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Bardfield, Lynda, 1984 (Box 31)
    - Benefits, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Bonus files, 1981-1983 (Box 31)
    - Budner, David, 1982 (Box 31)
    - Chicago Office, 1982-1985 (Box 31)
    - Creative Department, 1969 (Box 31)
    - Employee Stock Options, 1982 (Box 31)
    - Fine, Jeff, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Finkelstein, Ira, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Haley Associates, Inc., 1983 (Box 31)
    - Hong Kong Office, 1982 (Box 31)
    - International, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Kroll, Bob, 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Lerman, Al, 1983-1984 (Box 31)
    - Littleford, Ted, 1983 (Box 31)
    - MacMaster, Norman, 1983-1984 (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1983 (Box 32)
    - New York Office
      - General, 1982-1985 (Box 32)
      - Creative Department, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Policy correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 32)
    - Promotions, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Salary increases, 1981 (Box 32)
    - Scott, Lou, 1982 (Box 32)
    - Scott, Louis, 1982-1984 (Box 32)
    - Sugarman, Len, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Training programs, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Young, Jack M., 1983 (Box 32)
- Reports, 1971-1985, 3 boxes
  Contains reports and charts covering topics such as advertising techniques, research, media, industries, and demographics. Also includes annual reports, operations reviews and creative reviews for company-wide performance. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Advertising Agencies, 1982-1984 (Box 33)
  - American Advertising Federation, 1984 Jun. (Box 33)
  - Analytical Reports, 1983 (Box 33)
  - Annual Reports, 1978-1983, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Background of FCB Direct Marketing and International Direct Marketing, 1982 (Box 33)
  - Competitive Agency Review, 1983 Nov. (Box 33)
  - Corporate Research Plan, 1982 (Box 33)
  - Creative Organization Study, 1980 (Box 33)
  - Creative reviews, domestic offices, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Finance Committee Report to Communications Board, 1982 Feb. 17 (Box 33)
  - Financial memos and reports, 1981-1982, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box 33)
  - Financial memos and reports, 1981-1982 (continued), 3-5 of 5 folders (Box 34)
  - Financial reports, 1981, 7 folders (Box 34)
  - FCB and the Agency Business, 1983 Sept. (Box 34)
  - Grid Studies, 1982-1983 (Box 34)
  - Inflation - Supplemental Data, 1981 (Box 34)
  - Information Systems Survey, 1982 (Box 34)
  - Management Task Force Report, 1982, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - National Advertising Review Board
    - General files, 1973-1974 (Box 34)
    - Product Advertising and Consumer Safety Report, 1974 (Box 34)
  - New Communications Technologies, 1983-1984 (Box 34)
  - Operating Objectives, 1983 (Box 34)
  - Operating Plan for 1982-1984, 1982 (Box 34)
  - Political Advertising, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Report on the Dr. Group, 1982 (Box 35)
  - Report on Public Opinion on Political Advertising on Television, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Report on Public Reaction to Political Advertising, 1971 (Box 35)
  - Role of FCB in New Communication Technologies, 1982 (Box 35)
  - Role of Research at FCB, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Stock Option Awards, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Stockholder and Shareholder Reports, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Summary of Available Information on the Seagram Company, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Three-Year Management Plan for 1983-1985, Germany, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Three-Year Plan for 1983-1985, 1983 (Box 35)
  - U.S. Corporate Communications Plan, 1984-1985 (Box 35)
  - Value Line Investment Survey, 1981 (Box 35)
- Slides, 1956-1987 and undated, 2 boxes
  Contains slides of advertisements for FCB and competing agencies. Materials are divided into FCB and non-FCB categories. A separate category exists entitled O'Toole's Favorites, which includes advertisements from FCB and other agencies. Clients well represented include Clairol, Volkswagen and Frito-Lay.
  - General (Box 35)
    - Loose slides, 1983 and undated (Box 35)
    - O'Toole's Favorites, 1967-1970 and undated, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - FCB slides
    - Clairol, 1956-1966 and undated (Box 35)
    - Frito-Lay, 1971-1982 and undated (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous clients, 1972-1979 and undated (Box 35)
    - Sunkist, 1966 and undated (Box 35)
  - Non-FCB slides
    - Posters, 1972-1987 and undated (Box 35)
    - Prints, 1959-1984 and undated, 2 folders (Box 36)
- Writings and Speeches, 1969-1990 and undated, 7 boxes
  Contains primarily speeches written and delivered by O'Toole, relating to various advertising topics. Includes some speeches and articles written by other FCB staff, or other advertising professionals. Series also contains some files related to O'Toole's articles and publications, including his 1981 book, The Trouble With Advertising. Also includes articles on advertising by other authors. Items were arranged alphabetically by folder title. Where several versions of the same speech appeared, items were arranged by date of presentation. Where speech titles were not available, the title of the event was used as the folder title.
  - Advance Promotion and On-Site Activities, Worldwide Managers Meeting, 1982 (Box 36)
  - Advertising Age articles, 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - Advertising Age Creative Workshop, 1985 (Box 36)
  - Advertising: A Top-Level Responsibility
    - Northwestern Management Alumni Association, 1985 Aug. 7 (Box 36)
    - Advertising: A Top-Level Repsonsibility, Royal Bank of Canada, 1985 Oct. 15 (Box 36)
  - Advertising Business Circa 1984, undated (Box 36)
  - Advertising article for Compton Encyclopedia, 1982 Apr. 30 (Box 36)
  - Advertising in the '80s: Looking Backward into the Future
    - Advertising Age Conference, 1978 Aug. 21 (Box 36)
    - Association Nacional Anunciantes de México, 1978 Nov. (Box 36)
    - Hiram Walker International Conference, 1979 May 7 (Box 36)
    - Magazine Publishers Association, 1979 Apr. 19 (Box 36)
    - Milan Meeting, 1978 Oct. (Box 36)
  - Advocacy Advertising, 1974, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Advocacy Advertising - Act II
    - Fortune Corporate Communications Seminar, 1975 Mar. 4 (Box 36)
    - Phoenix Advertising Club, 1976 Mar. 22 (Box 36)
  - Affiliated Advertising Agencies International, 1985 Apr. (Box 36)
  - Are Grace Slick and Tricia Nixon Cox the Same Person?
    - Houston Advertising Club, 1973 Jan. 9 (Box 36)
    - New York Society of Security Analysts, 1973 Aug. 31 (Box 37)
  - Articles packet, 1982 (Box 37)
  - Atavistic Need to Speak to Graduating Classes, AAAA IAAS Graduation, 1984 Jun. (Box 37)
  - Background material, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Basic Research Techniques, 1984 Jan. (Box 37)
  - Be the Best, Worldwide Managers Meeting, 1978 Apr. 11 (Box 37)
  - Being Half-Creative
    - AAAA Western Regional Convention, 1983 Oct. 21 (Box 37)
    - Denver Advertising Federation, 1985 Oct. (Box 37)
    - Magazine Publishers Association, 1984 May 23, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Book of Advertising Tests, Lord & Thomas, undated (Box 37)
  - Books by O'Toole, reference material, 1977 (Box 37)
  - CLIO Awards Show, 1982 Jun. 11 (Box 37)
  - Consumer's Viewpoint: A History of FCB, Worldwide Creative Conference, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Conversation with John O'Toole, P.R. News, 1984 Sept. (Box 37)
  - Creative Directors Can Pinch Pennies, Association of National Advertising Workshop on Television Advertising, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Creative Thinking, speech materials, 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Creativity Around the World, Association of National Advertisers, 1984 Nov. 14 (Box 37)
  - Creativity, Design and the Brain, Betty Edwards, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Dunkin' Donuts National Marketing Seminar, 1972, Dec. 12 (Box 37)
  - Election of 1952, Northwestern University, 1984 Nov. 2 (Box 37)
  - Food Chip presentation, 1984 Nov. (Box 37)
  - Four Common Misconceptions, New York Society of Security Analysts, 1979 Dec. 14 (Box 37)
  - From One Person to Another, John O'Toole, 1977 (Box 37)
  - Future Shock, Los Angeles Advertising Club, 1971 Jan. 27 (Box 37)
  - Great Outdoors
    - Atlanta Advertising Club, 1985 Jun. 10 (Box 37)
    - James Webb Fund Address, 1985 Mar. 5 (Box 38)
    - San Francisco Advertising Club, 1985 Feb. 13 (Box 38)
    - Traffic Audit Bureau, 1986 Apr. 14 (Box 38)
  - High Dudgeon Replaces Low Profile, Life Advertisers Association and Institute of Life Insurance, 1974 Mar. 1 (Box 38)
  - How to Develop and Expose Better Advertising, John Philip Jones, 1984 (Box 38)
  - How to Handle Public Relations for Your Advertising Agency, Len Matthews, 1983 (Box 38)
  - If Elected, Here's What I'd Do About Political TV Spots, San Francisco Advertising Club, 1971 Nov. 17 (Box 38)
  - Illusions and Conclusions About Great Advertising
    - AAAA Western Regional Conference, 1984 Oct. 18 (Box 38)
    - AAAA Southern Regional Annual Meeting, 1985 Feb. 9 (Box 38)
  - I'm Going to Take a Very Simple, Clear Stand..., AAAA Eastern Regional Annual Conference, 1981 Jan. 29 (Box 38)
  - Image of Advertising
    - AAAA New England Senior Management Seminar, 1984 Sept. 17 (Box 38)
    - AAAA Senior Management Seminar, 1984 Nov. 8 (Box 38)
    - Advertising Club of Baltimore, 1985 Apr. 16 (Box 38)
    - American Chamber of Commerce-Japan Marketing Association, 1984 Apr. 24 (Box 38)
    - Los Angeles Advertising Club, 1985 Jan. 23 (Box 38)
    - Norway version, 1983 (Box 38)
  - Image Problem in the U.S.: A Status Report, AAAA Annual Meeting, 1984 Mar. 10 (Box 38)
  - In the Beginning was the Poster, Greenwich Library, 1985 Jan. 15 (Box 38)
  - International Advertising Association, 1982 Sept. 14 (Box 38)
  - International Advertising Film Festival, 1985 (Box 38)
  - International Film Festival, Cannes, 1985 Jun. (Box 38)
  - International Tourism and Its Implications for Bermuda, Bermuda Council on International Affairs, 1985 Sept. 26 (Box 38)
  - Introduction to Excerpt, book publicity, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Is Susan Ford Really Patty Hearst?, San Francisco Advertising Club, 1975 Sept. 3 (Box 38)
  - Joy of the Unexpected
    - Dallas Advertising League, 1985 May 7 (Box 38)
    - Worldwide Creative Conference, 1985 (Box 38)
  - Judge Greene, Where Are You Now That We Need You?, Television Bureau of Advertising, 1985 Feb. 20 (Box 38)
  - Kind of Advertising We're Going to Make and How It's Going to Make Us, 1971 May 17 (Box 38)
  - Magazine Day, 1985 Apr. 18 (Box 39)
  - Making Ads, John O'Toole, 1976 (Box 39)
  - Marketing in the 1980s--New Questions and Old Answers, New York University Business Forum Luncheon, 1984 Feb. 23 (Box 39)
  - Marronniers de Boulogne, Alain Malraux, 1978 (Box 39)
  - Media Function, undated (Box 39)
  - Mexican Advertising Agencies Association talk, 1982 Nov. 4 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous talks files, 1981 (Box 39)
  - Momentum or Inertia, 1984 Marketing Conference, 1984 Oct. 16 (Box 39)
  - Network Television: The OPEC of Media, AAAA Media Day, 1983 May 5 (Box 39)
  - New Questions and Old Answers
    - AAAA Advertising Educator Seminar, 1984 Mar. 30 (Box 39)
    - Association of National Advertisers Advertising Financial Management Workshop, 1984 May 7 (Box 39)
  - New York House Ad
    - New York Society of Security Analysts, 1978 Mar. 15 (Box 39)
    - Shareholders Meeting presentation, 1978 May 16 (Box 39)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts presentations, 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - New York Times speech, 1982 Sept. 30 (Box 39)
  - Northwestern University, Kellogg School Alumni Association Luncheon, 1985 Aug. 7 (Box 39)
  - Not People But Persons, New Business Presentation, 1970 May 13 (Box 39)
  - Notes for Evaluating Campaigns, FCB Board of Directors, 1984 Aug. 14 (Box 39)
  - Now, the Good News, International Newspaper Advertising Executives, 1975 Jan. 28 (Box 39)
  - Occasional Paper, B.A. Tucker, 1982 (Box 39)
  - O'Toole speeches, miscellaneous files, 1982-1984 (Box 39)
  - O'Toole speech notes, 1984 (Box 39)
    [Includes notes for speeches at World New Products Conference and Conference Board-Marketing Conference.]
  - Our Great Creative Heritage, Worldwide Creative Directors Conference, 1985 Jan. 28 (Box 39)
  - Outline for the 80s, Lake Bluff Group, 1980 (Box 40)
  - Person to Person magazine, 1981-1983 (Box 40)
  - Political Advertising, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Presentations, 1975-1979 (Box 40)
  - Presentation Techniques, Ron Hoff, 1977 (Box 40)
  - Pressure Groups and Network Television Advertising, 1981 (Box 40)
  - Pressure Groups and Satellites, Australian Association of National Advertisers, 1982 Oct. 25 (Box 40)
  - Purely Personal Print Preferences, 1969-1972 (Box 40)
  - Quest for Fire, Paul C. Harper, AAAA Annual Convention, 1984 (Box 40)
  - Quest for the Symmetrical Potato Chip, World New Products Conference, 1984 Oct. 9 (Box 40)
  - Real Thing, Tom Stoppard, 1983 (Box 40)
  - Role of Account Management, 1977 (Box 40)
  - Role of Advertising, FTC Open Hearing on Advertising, 1971 Nov. 1 (Box 40)
  - San Francisco Advertising Club, 1985 (Box 40)
  - Scientific Advertising, Claude Hopkins, with Introduction by John O'Toole, 1980 (Box 40)
  - Second Splits, Atlantic magazine, 1984 (Box 40)
  - Seldom Have I Seen..., Adweek Seminar, 1984 Oct. 2 (Box 40)
  - Some Thoughts on Polynesian Navigation, AAAA Annual Meeting, 1985 May 18 (Box 40)